你在看原住民裸女吗？
Are you looking at naked tribeswomen?
不是，你看
No,look.
这是猪耶
That's a pig.
我知道，你看它的奶头多大
I know. But look at the knobs on it!
艾蜜莉的表妹 竟然把我赶出来
Emily's cousin kicked me out.
什么？ 为什么？
-What? -Why?
跟老婆的表妹分租公寓 要是之后又离婚
When you sublet from your wife's cousin...then you divorce,
表妹就会突然把房子要回去
sometimes the cousin wants his apartment back.
怎么可以？你们没签约吗？
Didn't you sign a lease?
谁跟亲戚租公寓还签约？
Who needs a lease when it's "family"?
你可以跟我们住
You can stay with us.
我们照顾你 没错
We'll take care of ya!Oh, yeah! Absolutely!
包在我们身上
Anything you need man!
你心情好一点就说一声 好让我们取笑你的头发
But you have to let us know when you feel better so we can make fun of your hair.
对
Yeah
没问题
You got it.
谢谢你们，我太感激了
Thanks,I really appreciate this.
我得回去打包行李了
I'm going to get packing again.
我最近不断搬家 简直像是游民（nomad）
I've been moving around so much that I feel like a nomad.
怎么了？
-What?
他以为你说的是“生殖腺”（gonad）
-He thought you said gonad.
本集播出：“罗斯搬入”
The One Where Ross Moves ln
主演：珍妮佛安妮斯顿
寇妮考克斯
丽莎库卓
麦特勒布兰
马修派瑞
大卫修蒙
莫妮卡，要是每家餐厅 都跟你的一样干净
If every place were this clean,
我就要失业了
I'd have a tough time making a living.
拜托，赖瑞
Oh,Larry!
卫生稽查员收佣金吗？
Do health inspectors work on commission?
不，不过收红包
No,bribes.
我可以笑吧？
-It's okay to laugh?
当然，我开玩笑啦 那好
-I was just kidding.-Okay
我去检查厨房地板
-I'll check the kitchen floor.
请自便，赖瑞
-Okay，Knock yourself out.Larry
我绝对不会违规
I don't get violations.
地板干净到 豆子都能捡起来吃
You could eat beans off that floor.
别吃喔，否则你就违规了
But don't,because that'd be a violation.
真可口
Yummy!
你说赖瑞？
Larry？
我也愿意让他检查我厨房地板
Yeah,I'd let him check out my kitchen floor.
98分
A ninety-eight.
你没戴帽子所以扣两分 因为违反第五条规定
I deducted two points for not wearing your hat.That is a Section 5 violation.
赖瑞，亲爱的
Now look,Larry,honey.
第五条条文是我写的 在厨房才要戴帽子
I wrote the book on Section 5.You only need to wear it in the kitchen.
你的帽子呢？
-Where's your hat?
在厨房，我进去拿
-ln the kitchen. I'll get it.
扣两分
There's the two points!
你自己写的书应该认真读
You should really read that book you wrote.
你看到帽子在厨房
You saw the hat in the kitchen
知道她会不戴帽子进去取
and knew she'd go in hatless to get it.
你可以当卫生稽查员 兼侦探了
You could have your own health inspector detective show.
你太客气了
I don't know about that.
我可以演你的助手薇达
But then I could be your sidekick,Voonda.
薇达可以留电话给我 我就能约她出去吃饭
Maybe I could ask Voonda to dinner sometime?
她一定很开心
She would love that...
因为你知道哪家餐厅才卫生
...since you know all the clean places to eat.
我再打给你 好
I'll call you.Okay
他真幽默
He's so funny!
“中央咖啡馆”
谢了 谢谢
Thank you.
罗斯还好吧？ 还在为艾蜜莉伤心吗？
How's Ross doing since all the Emily stuff?
心情不太好
He's not great.
不过还死不了
But he's dealing with it.
等等，你该不会… 拜托，不可能
Wait,you're not…-Oh honey please，No
我不可能再跟罗斯交往
I can't get started with all that Ross stuff again.
他还要失魂落魄好长一段时间
He'll be screwed up for a long time.
况且你也知道 我不喜欢刚离婚的男人
Besides,I don't go for guys right after they get divorced.
对，还有五分钟就结婚的人你才要
Right,you only go for them five minutes before they get married.
我要两磅爪哇摩卡咖啡
-Two pounds of mocha java.
是丹尼，你们还会出去吗？
-It's Danny.Are you going to go out again?
不知道
I don't know.
上次出去一次之后 他就没再打给我
He hasn't called since we went out.
我们只在走廊上打情骂俏
I see him in the hallway. We flirt.
我笑得花枝乱颤却没下文
I'm all ha-ha-ha-ha，And then nothing.
嘿
Hey
嗨，丹尼
Hi Danny
你很渴吧？
Wow,thirsty.
我周六要办派对 庆祝我搬新家
I'm having a party on Saturday. Sort of a housewarming thing.
真有意思 真好
-Fun. -Great!
我也希望周六赶快到
I'm looking forward to it.
是啊
Yeah
那我走了
Okay，See you!
看来他新家不欢迎我们
So I guess we won't be warming his house.
很好，我知道他在玩什么把戏
All right,I see what he's doing.
他故意不约我 因为他要我主动约他
He's not asking me out because he wants me to ask him out.
可是你不会屈尊的
And you won't do that.
没错
That's right!
否则主导权就落在他手里
Because that would give him the control.
他现在故意说什么要办派对 要我暗示他约我
So now he comes up with this "I've got a party" thing...to get me to hint for an invitation
弄巧成拙
Blew up in his face,didn't it?
所以他根本没有要办派对
So there is no party?
有，当然有
No,there's a party. There's a party.
但是控制权  我们两个都想争取
But the power?That is still up for grabs.
你听得懂吗？
You follow me?
应该吧
I think so.
你说他喜欢你 所以故意不约你
So he won't invite you to his party because he likes you?
就是这样
Exactly!
可是他为什么不约我？
Then why didn't he invite me?
故意吊我胃口
To throw me off.
罗斯
Ross
亲爱的室友
Hey,roomies!
你把家里布置得真温馨
I love what you've done with the place.
我知道箱子堆得到处都是
I know it's a lot of boxes.
我要再次感谢你们收容我
-I appreciate you letting me stay here.
没问题
-Not a problem.
既然你要在这里住一阵子 干脆录一段你的留言
Since you'll be here a while....we could put your name on the answering machine.
是啊 希望你们别介意
Oh yeah-I hope you don't mind...
我已经录了一段爵士风格的
but I kind of already jazzed it up a little.
你们听
Check it out.
我们一定一定会回你电话
We will we will call you back
很酷吧？
Pretty cool.
你也是假笑吧？
-You're fake laughing too,right?
不过眼泪是真的
-The tears are real.
你今晚真漂亮
You look beautiful this evening.
再给我看一次徽章
Show me the badge again.
真是闪闪发亮
Shiny.
我去洗个手 因为我下班就直接过来
You mind if I wash up? Because I came straight from work
谁晓得这两个宝贝碰过什么
And who knows where these babies have been?
你真是一刻不停啊
You are just nonstop!
我们必须立刻走 为什么？
-We're out of here. -Why?
我刚经过厨房就看到十项违规
Just walking past the kitchen I saw 1 0 violations.
我要勒令他们停业
I'm shutting this place down!
你办得到吗？
-You have the power to do that?
有这个就可以
-This does.
那就让他们停业吧
Shut it down.
嘿
Hey
你做什么？
What are you doing?
没什么
Nothing.
你造了一个城堡？
You built a fort,didn't you?
差不多
Kind of.
天啊，是他的空气清净器
Oh,my God! The air purifier. Ross' air purifier.
我大学四年只听得到…
All I heard for four years through college was....
老兄，你不该只闷在宿舍里
You should have gone out once in a while.
我讨厌这东西
-I hate this thing!
钱德，罗斯是我们的好友
-Come on,Chandler.Ross is our friend.
他现在需要我们帮忙
He needs us right now.
成熟点，进来城堡看电视吧
So why don't you be a grownup and come watch TV in the fort?
赖瑞竟然勒令楚门餐厅停业 我很喜欢那家餐厅
Can't believe that Larry closed down Churman's. I love that place.
你应该听听他们有哪些违规
You should have heard about all their violations.
赖瑞说他们该改名蟑螂餐厅
Larry said that they should call it Vermin's.
那家伙实在太搞笑了
That guy just plain kills me.
嗨，丹尼
Oh hi Danny
我来请你们参加明晚的派对
I wanted to invite you to the party.
谢了，我们有时间就过去
Thanks,I'll try to stop by.
不过我可能有事
Actually,I think I'm going to be busy.
是吗？
You are?
对，我上次跟你说要参加比赛
Remember,I've got that gala?
什么比赛？
What's the gala for?
赛船会
It's a regatta gala.
你会开帆船？
Do you sail?
不会，可是我赞助比赛
No,but I support it.
好吧，明晚见咯
I hope I see you tomorrow night.
好
Okay
保重
Take care.
他果然用这招对吧
Walked right into that one,didn't he?
哪一招？
What one?
你希望他邀你参加派对 他也来啦
You wanted him to invite you and he did.
可是他等到最后一刻才来
He waited until the last minute.
如果我答应，他就知道 我没事可做等着接受他的邀请
So if I said yes......he'd know I had nothing better to do than wait for his invitation to his stupid party.
但是我说不去 所以还是我占上风
But I said no...which puts me back in the driver's seat.
真好，所以换他出招咯？
Great. So the ball is in his court?
出招？他没招可出了
Ball?No,there's no ball.
菲比，你吃不吃？
Hey,Phoebe,you want to join us?
好啊，哪里买的？
-Oh,sure,yeah. Where is this from?
三林餐厅
-It's from Sun Ling's.
赖瑞跟我提过三林的菜
Oh,Larry just told me something about Sun Ling.
算了，多谢
Oh,no,thank you.
乔伊，麻烦你
Joey,please.
对不起
Sorry.
嗨，孩子们
Hello,children.
要不要玩足球？求求你？
You want to play some foosball? Please?
好吧 不…
Okay.-No…
游戏桌搬进我房间了
We moved the table into my room
因为外面太多箱子，进来吧
because of all the boxes.Come on!
我有个问题
I have one question.
这是什么东西？
What is the deal with this?
小布偶乔伊说再见？
Bye-bye,little puppet Joey hand?
不是，叫我闭嘴的手势
No,the quiet down thing.
你是说这样啊
You mean this.
我不知道我还能憋多久
I don't know how much more I can take.
他竟然拿我的海滩游侠录影带 去录什么虫子
Did you know he taped over my Baywatch tape with a show about bugs?
天呐！要是里面原本是A片呢？
My God!What if that had been porn?
别激动，或许你憋得很难过 可是他是罗斯
All right,this may be tough but it's Ross.
我跟他大学四年都忍过来了
I survived college with him.
我或许还可以再忍一阵子
I guess I can hold out a little longer.
来玩吧 好
Let's have a game.
不要… 万岁
No…Yes!
两位
Fellas?
他非走不可
So he's out of here.
这里有没有东西可吃？
Got anything to eat?
我刚才去强诺买鸡块 那里竟然停业了
I went to Jono's for some chicken and it was closed.
我带赖瑞去，餐厅不合规定 我们勒令他们停业
I took Larry there,but it was all violated,so we shut it down.
菲比，这家伙不断关掉 大家喜欢去的餐馆
If this guy keeps closing our favorite places,
以后我们上哪吃饭？
where will we eat?
不晓得，干净的地方？
I don't know. Clean places?
嗯，是啊
Yum!
是丹尼
It's Danny.
别让他进来，我现在 应该去看帆船赛了
Don't let him in! I'm supposed to be at a gala.
我们马上过去
We'll be right there.
不能说大赛还没开始吗？
Can't you say it's later?
什么？哪种帆船在晚上比赛？
What kind of a regatta gala starts at night?
假的那种
The fake kind.
嗨，我想借个勺子，你有吗？
-I need a ladle. You got a ladle?
我们有
-We have a ladle.
谢了，待会儿见 好
Thanks，See you at the party.-Okay
你们知道赖瑞会怎么回答吗？
You know what Larry would say?
他会说，“勺后见”
He'd say,"See you ladle."
我看完了，你要看吗，罗斯？ 有体育、国际、租屋版
I'm done. You want anything? Sports? International?Apartment listings?
我要体育版 我要
I'll take sports.Mine!
那就国际版好了 我也要
All right,international.That's mine too.
我是意大利裔
I'm ltalian.
那就看看租屋广告吧 不过报纸上向来没好房子
I could check apartment listings,though there's never anything here.
第7页也没有吗？
Not even on page seven?
有啊，你说得对
You're right.
有个地方价钱很公道 两间卧室、上班也近
Here's an affordable place.Two-bedroom,close to work.
可是还要五周才能搬进去
It's available in five weeks.
圈起来的那个呢？
What about that circled one?
不知道耶，就套房来说有点贵
I don't know,It's kind of expensive for a studio.
可是现在就能搬进去
But it's available now.
对不对？
Isn't it?
的确是
Yes,it is.
我们去看看
Let's go look at it!
好，我们走 走吧
Okay,There we go!
对了，伙计们
Oh-oh-ooh,hey guys,
可不可以大家分摊买滤芯？
I was wondering if you guys would uh,maybe chip in on some new air filters for the purifier?
毕竟空气清净器大家都有用到
I mean,after all,we are all using it.
快点走 好
Let's go quicker!
天啊
Oh,my God!
你们看这个厨房…兼浴室
Look at this kitchen/bathroom.
太棒了，可以一边煮饭 一边洗澡
That's great! So you can cook while in the tub.
房东真是太聪明了
Somebody was using his head.
再看看其他地方
Let's check out the rest of the place.
就这么大了
I think this is it.
我们应该看看别间公寓
I don't know. Maybe we should keep looking.
可是这地方马上就能搬进来
But this place is available now.
对啊，你不会愿意 继续跟我们住五周
You don't want to be stuck with us for five weeks.
是啊
Yeah
你觉得我应该租下？
So you think I should take this place?
这里很棒啊
It's perfect!
你呢？
How about you?
这里有厨房兼浴室耶
Kitchen,slash,bathroom.
好吧，我懂了
I see what you guys are saying.
我下楼填申请表
I'll go downstairs and fill out an application.
我们是坏人
We are bad people.
他知道我们想赶他走
He knew we were trying to get rid of him.
他知道了
He knew
我们厨房能不能装浴缸？
Could we get a bathtub in our kitchen?
要去吃饭了吗？
Ready for dinner?
当然 很好
-Absolutely. -Great.
你上次不是说要去布里克街 那家意大利餐厅？
You wanted to go to the ltalian place on Bleecker St.?
我爱死那里了
I love that place!
所以…不行
So,no.
“李赛提老妈”呢？
How about Mama Lozetti's?
没问题
Sure.
不知道那瓶牛奶放多久了？
How long has that milk been sitting out?
这地方非常干净
No,this place is totally healthy.
那瓶牛奶是我的
This milk is mine.
今天买的，我突然想喝牛奶
I bought this today...because I was thirsty for milk,you know?
我们走吧
Okay,let's go.
老兄
Hey,buddy.
你知道卫生规则 11条B款吗？
Are you familiar with Section 11-B of the Health Code
垃圾应该从后门拿出去
that requires all refuse material out the back exit？
可是这样就得从干洗店绕路
But then I'd have to go all the way around the dry cleaner place.
你宁可方便也不顾卫生？
So you're saying you'd choose convenience over health?
请你喝咖啡好吗？
Would you be interested in a free coffee?
赖瑞，别这样
Stop,Larry.
你能不能别老想着工作？
Can't you just be Larry and not Larry the health inspector guy?
一开始还很刺激
It was exciting at first.
现在简直哪家餐厅也去不了
But now,it's like,so where are we going to eat ever?
不然我口头警告他好了
I suppose I could give him a warning.
谢谢
Thank you.
快走啊
Go,go!
要是吃饱饭后你还想抓人
If,after dinner,you still need to bust someone...
我知道哪个热狗摊老板 喜欢挖鼻子
...I know a hot dog vendor who picks his nose.
搞不好我们做的是好事 帮助罗斯早点恢复正常
Maybe we did good,helping Ross get back on his feet.
况且那地方实在不错 是啊
That was a nice place.
虽然柜子不多 不过可以用袋子装好挂在窗外
No closet space,but he could hang his stuff out the window in a bag.
是啊
Yeah
现在该怎么办？
What do we do?
不知道
I don't know.
要吃披萨吗？
Maybe pizza?
我说的是罗斯
About Ross!
喂
Hello
我是，是公寓经理 罗斯填我们当介绍人
Oh yeah!It's the apartment manager. Ross put us as references.
罗斯绝对是好人 这人非常可靠
Ross is the greatest guy. He's very reliable
不过他养了一只大狗
Of course,he has a big,huge dog
半夜叫个不停
that barks into the night.
是啊，谁不喜欢狗啊？
Well,who doesn't love dogs?
他是个踢踏舞者
He's a tap dancer.
这的确是失传的艺术
Yes,some would say that is a lost art.
他是男妓
He's a pimp!
没错，就是男妓
There you go. He's a pimp.
他是会跳踢踏舞的男妓
He's a big,tap-dancing pimp!
喂
Hello
我准备好了
-Okay,honey,I'm ready.
你想干什么？
-What are you doing?
我要晃进派对
I am going to wander into the party
装做一副 刚从帆船赛回来的样子
and I will be all,you know:"l don't need this,I'm coming from a regatta gala."
你这是从书上学来的吗？
Did you get this out of a book?
亲爱的莫妮卡，书如人生啊
Monica,honey,this is as real as it gets.
该死，这可不行 他就站在那里
This is never going to work. He's right there.
去打声招呼就行啦
Just go say hi.
不行，我得从楼下走上来 假装我刚从外面回来
I have to go downstairs and back up,as if I'm coming home from the gala.
你去引开他的注意力 但是别太性感
So just go distract him. But don't be sexy.
丹尼
Hey Danny
怎么样？
What's going on?
这个派对真不错，食物也很好
This is a great party. Great food.
大部分派对都只有薯片、沙拉 薯片、沙拉
You know,most parties,it's all chips and salsa,chips and salsa.
这是什么？
What's this?
沙拉
Salad.
这又是什么？
And what's this?
面包
Bread.
你不是厨师吗？
Aren't you a chef?
嘿，瑞秋
Hi Rachel
对了，你今晚要办派对
Right,tonight was your party.
你穿得真漂亮 幸好你赶回来了
You look great! I'm glad you made it.
比赛总不能没完没了
Well,you know,the gala had to end sometime.
你别走开，我马上回来
Don't go anywhere. I'll be right back.
没问题
Yeah sure
你说现在换谁出招啦？
Whose court is the ball in now?
你不是说他没招可出？
I thought there wasn't a ball.
拜托，他很高兴我来了 而且还叫我别走开
Come on. He's glad I came. He doesn't want me to go anywhere.
我们两个现在是你来我往
Ball's flying all over the place.
瑞秋，这是我朋友汤姆
This is my friend,Tom.
这就是我跟你提过的小姐
This is the girl I told you about.
拜托，你跟人提过我？
Come on! You telling people about me?
你们一定会一拍即合的
I think you two could really hit it off.
我回派对了
I'm gonna go mingle.
你在布鲁明戴尔百货上班？
So you work at Bloomingdale's?
我妈妈称呼那里是“布明儿”
My mom calls it "Bloomies."
真不错，稍息，大兵
At ease,soldier!
什么？
I'm sorry?
没关系，汤姆，你别装了 我知道你们搞什么鬼
You can just drop the act. I know what's going on.
你是丹尼的舵手对不对？
You're Danny's wingman,right?
你们交情老、感情好
You guys are best buds,frat bros.
我要去…找朋友
I'm going to go talk to a friend.
请便，去找你朋友吧
Yeah,you go talk to your friend.
告诉他，“这招漂亮”
Go tell him,"Nice try."
他真是出招连连 不过我可是招招都破
He just keeps lobbing them up...and I keep knocking them right out of the park.
我想喝杯饮料 我也要
I think I need a drink.-Yeah
98、99、100
Ninety-eight...ninety-nine…one hundred!
走吧
Okay. Go.
告诉你，我没问题
Dude,I'm telling you,I'm fine.
我扶住你了
Here we go,here we go.
嘿 嘿
Hey Hey
我没租到那间公寓
So I didn't get that apartment.
我的申请出了状况
Some problem with my application.
不可能吧？ 不会吧
You're kidding?No
不过菲比答应让我搬去跟她住
But Phoebe said I could stay at her place for a while,so....
你不能住菲比家 我们可是室友耶
Well,you can't stay with Phoebe. We're roomies.
我不能再占用你们的公寓
You don't need me taking up all your space.
反正这里大得很
We got plenty of space.
喇叭旁边还有空地
There's still some by that speaker.
住下来吧 对
Please,just stay.
你们确定？ 当然
Are you sure?-Definitely.
罗斯，你非住下来不可
-You have to stay.
好吧 就这么办
All right！
我是男妓对吧？
So I'm a pimp,huh?
算了
It's okay.
我知道我有时候很惹人烦 不过你们可以直说
Sometimes I can be a pain in the ass.But just talk to me.
明白告诉我哪里做得不好
Tell me if something bothers you.
我可以尽量改掉惹人嫌的习惯只要你们…
And I'll do everything I can to keep my annoying habits just....
显然你今天过得很充实
Well,I see you've had a very productive day.
不过戴牛仔帽也太过了吧？
The cowboy hat's a little much.
进来一起玩
Come on,it's fun!
好吧
All right.
这不是女人的帽子吗？
Isn't this a woman's hat?
还不赶快闭嘴去泡茶？
Stop talking crazy,and make us tea!